Lauren Usher

E: <u>usher@susqu.edu</u> – M: 570-855-3564141 – 18 Moyallen St, Wilkes Barre PA 18702

State Certified English Teacher

Analytical English teacher who undertakes complex assignments, conducts thorough research to meet student goals, and communicates with all levels of management and students to deliver strong results. Applies practical knowledge of lesson planning, differentiation, and classroom management to deliver strong results based on the needs of both the school and students. Excels in challenging, fast past settings that require direct, urgent engagement with both students and management.

Lesson Planning – Assessment – Ambassador – Statistical Analysis – Differentiated Development – Client Engagement – Project Management

Education

Bachelor of Secondary Education (cum laude, university honors) Susquehanna University - Selinsgrove, PA – 2012

Professional Experience

Shikellamy Middle School, Sunbury, PA Student Teacher, January 2012 – May 2012

- Performed all of the responsibilities of a full time teacher
- Developed daily lesson plans and long term unit plans for four classes of over twenty students over the course of a semester by following PA standards
- Created alternative learning opportunities for multiple students with IEPs and ESL concerns
- Modified learning goals by analyzing information compiled from a variety of different kinds of assessments Amazon

Process Assistant, May 2015 - Present

- Managed up to 80 associates to process over a million units in the case mods with a record of over 5,000 units processed per hour
- Became a point of contact in case mods on a primary shift while a new manager was being assigned
- Took ownership of misdivert, the recirculation line, the roster, and the conveyor in front of fluid load
- Became a ship clerk in fluid load and consistently achieved an upwards of 20,000 diverts, breaking the record across all shifts
- Spearheaded the stack mentor program

Warehouse Associate, January 2014 – May 2015

- Accepted a position as an ambassador
- Ensured compliance with SOP by training associates using established PMVs
- · Received unlocker, PIT, and jams training

- Addressed safety concerns around PIT equipment and jams and and area organization
- Attained the four levels of problem solve training including sort, EOL, and aging/IOL/workflow
- Streamlined black pallet sleeve process in EOL problem solve by communicating with outbound management, addressing the root cause, and updating the SOP
- Lead the LP Line